Weight initialization is really about
权重初始化的目标是
giving models the best chance to learn when training.
在训练过程中为模型带来最好的学习机会
Since many models rely on iteratively improving by looking at the mistakes they've made,
很多模型的学习方式是通过查看犯过的错误迭代地改进自己
we want them to start out making more informative mistakes,
因此我们希望模型一开始犯的错更有参考性
ones that are instructive and provide information about how exactly a model can improve.
能够为模型到底该如何改进自己提供启发和信息
We found that this was not the case when we initialized with constant weight values.
我们发现如果初始化为常量权重值 则满足不了这种需求
So, it might make sense to take a totally different approach.
因此或许有必要采取完全不同的策略
Instead of setting everything to all zeros or all ones,
如果我们将所有权重都初始化为彼此不同的唯一数字
what if we want to have all of our weights initialized as unique numbers?
而不是全设为 0 或 1 会怎么样？
The best way to do this is to randomly grab a bunch of
最佳方式是随机选择一批唯一数字
unique numbers which we can do by sampling from a probability distribution.
这些数字是从概率分布中抽样的数字
A good solution for getting these random weights
获取随机权重的很好方法是
is to sample from a uniform distribution.
从均匀分布中抽样
A uniform distribution has equal probability of picking any number from within a range.
均匀分布使我们能以同等概率从某个范围中挑选任何数字
We'll be picking values from a continuous distribution,
我们将从连续分布中挑选值
so the chance of picking the exact same number is very low.
因此挑选完全相同的数字的概率很低
First, I'll show you what these values might look like by using
首先我将演示这些值看起来如何
a helper function that displays a set of random values as a histogram.
我将使用辅助函数将一组随机值显示为直方图
Here I'm using numpy's random.uniform
使用 NumPy 的 random.uniform 函数
function to pick random numbers from a uniform distribution.
从均匀分布中挑选随机数字
This function takes in a low and a high bound on the range of random values to generate.
此函数的输入参数包括要生成的随机值的范围上下限
Here I'm specifying that it should generate
这个数字表示应生成 1000 个随机值
1000 random values in a range from negative three to positive three.
范围从 -3 到 3
Here's the resulting histogram.
这是生成的直方图
A histogram is made of many rectangles
直方图由很多长条组成
whose height is proportional to the frequency of a certain value.
长条的高与某个值的频率成正比
In this case, our histogram is actually creating
这个直方图生成了 500 个区间
500 buckets for each of our a thousand generated values.
分别表示 1000 个生成的值
For a uniform distribution,
对于均匀分布
we should see that most buckets then contain two generated values,
大多数区间都包含两个生成的值
which we can see by this line two about here.
可以从这个线条 2 看出来
A few buckets have zero,
有些区间里
one or up to ten values in them,
有 0、1 到最多 10 个值
but this is just a little bit of randomness.
但这只是随机情况
In general, we should see that these values are
通常 这些值应该会
fairly uniformly distributed along this range.
沿着这个范围随机分布
By picking the initial weights of a model from a distribution like this,
通过从这样的分布中选择初始模型权重
we're incorporating some randomness that should help our model train.
我们引入了随机性 应该能够帮助训练模型
We can still set some constraints on which values our weights take.
我们还可以对权重取值设置限制条件
Now, that we've seen a uniform distribution,
看了均匀分布后
let's see how well our model trains if it's initialized with uniform weights.
下面看看如果初始化为均匀权重 模型训练效果如何
Where I'll set the low value to be zero and the high value to be one.
我将下限设为 0 上限设为 1
Here, I'll show you one other way besides in
除了在 init 类代码中初始化权重之外
our net class code to initialize the weights of the network.
我还将演示另一种方式
To define waits outside of the model definition,
要在模型定义代码之外定义权重
you can define a function that assigns weights by the type of network layer,
你可以定义一个函数 该函数会根据层级类型分配权重
then apply those weights to an initialize model using
然后使用 model.apply(fn) 将这些权重应用到初始化模型上
model.applyfn which applies a function to each model layer.
model.apply(fn) 会将一个函数应用到每个模型层级上
So here, I'm defining a function weights in it uniform.
在这里定义函数 weights_init_uniform
This will be applied to every single module in our model.
此函数将应用到模型中的每个模块上
Here I'm checking for any linear layers in our model.
在这里检查模型中是否有任何线性层级
For the weights in each linear layer,
对于每个线性层级中的权重
I'm going to apply a uniform distribution with a low range of zero and a high of one.
我将应用一个均匀分布 上下限分别为 0 和 1
Here I'm setting the bias to a constant value of zero.
在这里将偏差设为常量 0
Just like in n.net,
就像在 nn.init 中一样
there are a number of distributions that you can
你可以调用多种分布
call upon to initialize the weights of a network in this way.
并以这种方式初始化网络权重
Then there's one more step, to actually initialize a model with these weights,
还有一步 要用这些权重初始化模型
I'm going to instantiate a new model.
我将实例化新的模型
I'm going to call it model uniform and I'm going to set it equal to a default net.
称之为 model_uniform 并设为默认的 Net()
Notice I'm not passing in any constant weight value here.
注意 我没有传入任何常量权重值
Then to apply my uniform weights,
要应用均匀权重
I'm going to call apply weights on it uniform on this model.
我将对此模型调用 apply(weights _init_uniform)
Apply will recursively call
apply 将不断调用此初始化函数
my initialization function and apply uniform weights to every linear layer.
并将均匀权重应用到每个线性层级上
This will also print out some details about that model.
同时输出关于该模型的细节信息
Finally, I'm creating a model list of just length
最后创建一个长度为 1 的模型列表
one and I want to see how this uniform model performs.
看看这个均匀模型的效果
Here we can see that the loss still starts out fairly
可以看出损失一开始依然很高
high but it's decreasing fairly reliably.
但是能稳定地下降
After training for two epics,
训练两轮之后
our model gets around 33 percent accuracy which is much better than just guessing.
模型的准确率约为 33% 比随机猜测强多了
So, we know that we're on the right track.
因此我们的策略方向是对的